Hey, come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Joe, you take over.
Hi, Grandpa.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Pa.
He doesn't know you yet.
Here you are, big guy.
Give it to Grandpa.
"I hope you get well, Grandpa...
and I wish
I would see you soon.
Love, your grandson, Frank. "
Go with your mother.
Go ahead.
Take 'em downstairs.
Go on, Carlo.
You too.
Go on.
I got chicken cacciatore
for you, sweetheart.
- That's enough bread.
- I love bread.
But how much can you eat?
What's the matter with you, Carlo?
Shut up and set the table.
Since McCluskey's killing...
the police have been cracking down
on most of our operations.
And also the other families'.
Been a lot of bad blood.
They hit us,
so we hit them back.
Through our contacts
in the newspapers...
we've been able to put out
a lot of material...
about McCluskey being linked
with Sollozzo in the drug rackets.
See, things are
starting to loosen up.
Dad, I'm sending Fredo
to Las Vegas...
under the protection
of Don Francesco of L.A.
I want him to rest.
I'm going to learn
the casino business.
Yeah.
Where is Michael?
It was Michael
who killed Sollozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting
to work to bring him back now.
I want you to find out where that
little pimp Tattaglia is hiding.
I want his ass now-
right now.
- Hey, Sonny.
- What?
Things are starting to loosen up
a little bit.
If you go after Tattaglia,
all hell's going to break loose.
Let the smoke clear.
Pop can negotiate.
No, Pop can't do nothing till
he's better. I'm gonna decide-
All right, but your war's
costing us a lot of money.
Nothing's coming in.
We can't do business.
Neither can they.
Don't worry about it.
- We can't afford a stalemate.
- Then there ain't no more stalemate.
I'm gonna end it
by killing that old bastard.
You're getting a great reputation.
I hope you're enjoying it.
Do what I tell you to do!
Goddamn it, if I had a wartime
consigliere- a Sicilian-
I wouldn't be in this shape!
Pop had Genco.
Look what I got.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
Mom made a little dinner.
It's Sunday.
Niggers are having
a good time...
with our policy banks
up there in Harlem.
Driving them new Cadillacs,
paying 50% on a bet.
I knew that was gonna happen as soon
as they started making big money.
Papa never talked business
at the table in front of the kids.
- Shut up, Connie.
- Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
- You got that?
- Santino, don't interfere.
Sonny, Tom, I'd like to talk
to you, maybe after dinner.
I could be doing more
for the family.
We don't discuss business
at the table.
Corleone.
Hey, American!
Take me to America! G.I.!
Take me to America, G.I.
Clark Gable.
I apologize if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country...
and I meant no disrespect
to you or your daughter.
I'm an American hiding in Sicily.
My name is Michael Corleone.
There are people who would pay
a lot of money for that information.
But then your daughter
would lose a father...
instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter...
with your permission...
and under the supervision
of your family...
with all respect.
Apollonia.
Hey! I'm gonna knock you dizzy.
Save it for the library.
Come on. We gotta go
pick up my sister. Let's go.
What's the matter?
- It was my fault!
- Where is he?
Sonny, please. It was my fault.
I hit him.
I started a fight with him.
Please, Sonny.
I'm sorry.
I'm just gonna get a doctor
to come and take a look at you.
Sonny, please don't do anything.
What's the matter with you?
What am I gonna do?
Am I gonna make that baby an orphan
before he's born?
All right?
Still betting the Yankees
pretty heavy?
Tell him to stop
taking action, all right?
You lost enough money
last weekend to me.
Carlo, come here.
You touch my sister again,
I'll kill you.
Weren't expecting you.
You should call.
Yes, well, I have.
I've tried writing and calling.
Now, I wanna reach Michael.
Nobody knows where he is. We know
he's all right, but that's all.
- What was that?
- That's an accident.
But nobody was hurt.
Would you give this letter
to Michael, please?
Well, if I accepted that...
in a court of law they could prove
I have knowledge of his whereabouts.
Just be patient.
He'll get in touch with you.
I let my cab go.
Can I come in to call another one?
Come on. I'm sorry.
Come on.
Hello?
Is Carlo there?
- Who's this?
- This is a friend of Carlo’s.
Would you tell him that
I can't make it tonight until later?
Bitch.
- Dinner's on the table.
- I'm not hungry yet.
Your food is on the table.
It's getting cold.
- I'll eat out later.
- You told me to make you dinner.
Hey, vaffancolo, eh?
I'll vaffanculo you!
This little guinea brat.
That's it. Break it all,
you spoiled guinea brat.
Break it all!
That's it.
Break it all.
Why don't you bring
your whore home for dinner?
Maybe I will.
Why not?
- Now clean it up!
- Like hell I will!
Clean it up,
you guinea spoiled brat!
Clean it up!
You son of a bitch!
Come on, now! Kill me!
Be a murderer like your father!
- All you Corleones are murderers!
- I hate you!
- Come on!
- I'll kill you!
Kill me!
Get up!
Get out of here!
- I hate you!
- Now I'll kill you.
You guinea brat, you.
Get out here!
Connie, what's the matter?
I can't hear you. What is it?
Talk louder.
The baby's crying.
Santino, I can't understand-
I don't know.
I don't understand.
Yeah, Connie.
Listen, you wait there.
No, you just wait there.
- That son of a bitch.
- Sonny, what's the matter?
- Son of a bitch!
- What's the matter?
Damn it!
Open the goddamn gate.
Get off your ass.
- Sonny, come on!
- Get out of here!
Go after him.
Go on.
Son of a bitch.
Come on! Come on!
Give me a drop.
My wife is crying upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliere of mine...
I think you should tell your Don
what everyone seems to know.
I didn't tell Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake you
just now and tell you.
But you needed a drink first.
Now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
He's dead.
I want all inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
with the heads
of the five families.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
We need him now.
This is Tom Hagen
calling for Vito Corleone...
at his request.
Now, you owe your Don a service.
He has no doubt that
you will repay it.
Now, he will be at your
funeral parlor in one hour.
Be there to greet him.
Well, my friend...
are you ready
to do me this service?
Yes.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to use
all your powers...
and all your skills.
I don't want his mother
to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday...
Wednesday, Friday,
Sunday, Saturday.
- Fabrizio.
- Yes, sir?
Are you driving yourself, boss?
- Yes.
- Is your wife coming with you?
Take her to her father's house
till I know things are safe.
Anything you say, boss.
Don Barzini,
I want to thank you...
for helping me organize
this meeting here today.
And also the other heads
of the five families...
from New York and New Jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx.
From Brooklyn...
Philip Tattaglia.
And from Staten Island...
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And all the other associates
that came as far...
as from California
and Kansas City...
and all the other territories
of the country.
Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate
and so unnecessary.
Tattaglia lost a son...
and I lost a son.
We're quits,
and if Tattaglia agrees...
then I'm willing to let things
go on the way they were before.
We are all grateful to Don Corleone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him
as a man of his word.
A modest man.
He'll always listen to reason.
Yes, Don Barzini.
He's too modest.
He had all the judges
and politicians in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse
an accommodation?
All of you know me here.
When did I ever refuse,
except one time?
And why?
Because I believe
this drug business...
is gonna destroy us
in the years to come.
I mean, it's not like gambling
or liquor or even women...
which is something that
most people want nowadays...
and is forbidden to them by
the pezzonovante of the church.
Even the police departments
that have helped us in the past...
with gambling and other things...
are gonna refuse to help us
when it comes to narcotics.
And I believed that then...
and I believe that now.
Times have changed.
It's not like the old days...
when we could do
anything we want.
A refusal is not the act
of a friend.
If Don Corleone had all the judges
and politicians in New York...
then he must share them
or let others use them.
He must let us draw
the water from the well.
Certainly, he can present a bill
for such services.
After all, we are not Communists.
I also don't believe in drugs.
For years,
I paid my people extra...
so they wouldn't do
that kind of business.
Somebody comes to them and says,
"I have powders.
If you put up a three,
four-thousand-dollar investment...
we can make 50,000 distributing. "
So they can't resist. I want
to control it as a business...
to keep it respectable.
I don't want it near schools.
I don't want it sold to children.
That's an infamia.
In my city, we'll keep the traffic
in the dark people, the colored.
They're animals anyway,
so let them lose their souls.
I hoped that we could come here
and reason together.
As a reasonable man, I'm willing
to do whatever's necessary...
to find a peaceful solution
to these problems.
Then we are agreed.
The traffic in drugs
will be permitted but controlled.
Don Corleone will give us
protection in the east...
and there will be the peace.
But I must have strict assurance
from Corleone.
As time goes by and
his position becomes stronger...
will he attempt
any individual vendetta?
Look, we are all
reasonable men here.
We don't have to give assurances
as if we were lawyers.
You talk about vengeance.
Is vengeance gonna bring
your son back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forego the vengeance of my son.
But I have selfish reasons.
My youngest son...
was forced to leave this country...
because of this Sollozzo business.
All right.
And I have to make arrangements...
to bring him back here safely,
cleared of all these false charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
And if some unluc accident
should befall him-
if he should get shot
in the head by a police officer...
or if he should hang himself
in his jail cell...
of if he’s struck
by a bolt of lightening-
then I'm going to blame
some of the people in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But that aside...
let me say that I swear...
on the souls
of my grandchildren...
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.