I believe in America.
America has made my fortune.
And I raised my daughter
in the American fashion.
I gave her freedom, but I taught her
never to dishonour her family.
She found a boyfriend, not an Italian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out late.
I didn't protest.
Two months ago he took her for a drive
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey
and then they tried to
take advantage of her.
She resisted, she kept her honour.
So they beat her like an animal.
When I went to the hospital,
her nose was broken,
her jaw was shattered,
held together by wire.
She couldn't even weep
because of the pain.
But I wept. Why did I weep?
She was the light of my life.
Beautiful girl.
Now she will never be beautiful again.
Sorry.
I went to the police,
like a good American.
These two boys were brought to trial.
The judge sentenced them to three years
in prison, but suspended the sentence.
Suspended the sentence!
They went free that very day!
I stood in the courtroom like a fool.
Those two bastards, they smiled at me.
Then I said to my wife, "For justice,
we must go to Don Corleone."
Why did you go to the police?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me? Tell me
anything, but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
I want them dead.
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
I've known you many years, but this
is the first time you've asked for help.
I can't remember the last time
you invited me for a cup of coffee.
Even though my wife is godmother
to your only child.
But let's be frank here.
You never wanted my friendship.
And you were afraid to be in my debt.
I didn't want to get into trouble.
I understand.
You found Paradise in America.
You made a good living, had police
protection and there were courts of law.
You didn't need a friend like me.
But now you come to me and say,
"Don Corleone, give me justice."
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship. You don't
even think to call me Godfather.
You come on my daughter's wedding
day and ask me to murder for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice.
Your daughter is alive.
Let them suffer, then, as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonasera, Bonasera.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfully?
If you'd come in friendship,
the scum that ruined your daughter
would be suffering this very day.
And if an honest man like you should
make enemies, they'd be my enemies.
And then they would fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather?
Good.
Some day, and that day may never
come, I'll ask a service of you.
But until that day...
...accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
- Grazie, Godfather.
- Prego.
Give this to Clemenza.
I want people that aren't going to
get carried away.
We're not murderers,
in spite of what this undertaker says.
- Where's Michael?
- Don't worry, he'll be here.
We're not taking the picture
without Michael.
- What's the matter?
- It's Michael.
Don Barzini.
Hey, Paulie! Let me have some wine.
Paulie! More wine.
- You look terrific on the floor.
- Are you a dance judge or something?
Take a walk and do your job.
Sandra, watch the kids.
Don't let them run wild.
You watch yourself, all right?
20, 30 grand. In small bills, cash.
In that little silk purse.
If this were somebody else's wedding...
Sfortunato!
Hey, Paulie!
Stupid jerk!
What's the matter?
- Have to go back to work.
- Tom.
No Sicilian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don Corleone, I'm honoured and
grateful that you have invited me.
Get out of here!
It's a private party. Go on!
What is it? It's my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI don't respect nothing!
Come here, come here, come here!
...but towards the end, he was paroled
to help with the American war effort,
so for six months he's worked
in my pastry shop.
Nazorine, what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over,
this boy, Enzo, they want to
repatriate him back to Italy.
Godfather, I have a daughter.
You see, she and Enzo...
You want Enzo to stay in this country,
and your daughter to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr. Hagen. Thank you.
Wait till you see the wedding cake
I made for your daughter!
The bride, the groom and the angel...
- Who should I give this job to?
- Not to our paisà.
Give it to a Jew Congressman in
another district. Who else is on the list?
Hey, Michael!
He's not on the list,
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this necessary?
He didn't expect to be invited to the
wedding, so he wanted to thank you.
Don Corleone, I'm honoured and
grateful that you have invited me
on the wedding day of your daughter.
May their first child be a masculine child.
Michael...
That man over there
is talking to himself.
See that scary guy over there?
- He's a very scary guy.
- What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi.
He helps my father out sometimes.
Michael, he's coming over here!
You look terrific!
My brother Tom Hagen,
Miss Kay Adams.
Your father's been asking for you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Why does your brother
have a different name?
My brother Sonny found Tom Hagen
in the street.
He had no home,
so my father took him in.
He's been with us ever since.
He's a good lawyer.
Not a Sicilian. I think he's
going to be consigliere.
- What's that?
- That's a...
...like a counsellor, an advisor.
Very important for the family.
You like your lasagne?
Don Corleone.
I'm honoured and grateful
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding.
On the day of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope that their first child
will be a masculine child.
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
- For your daughter's bridal purse.
- Thank you, Luca. Most valued friend.
Don Corleone, I'm going to leave you
now, because I know you're busy.
Thank you.
Signora Corleone!
No!
Senator Cauley apologised for not
coming, but said you'd understand.
Also some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
Johnny! Johnny!
I love you!
He came all the way from California.
I told you he'd come!
- He's probably in trouble again.
- He's a good godson.
Johnny, Johnny! Sing a song!
You never said you knew
Johnny Fontane!
- Sure. You want to meet him?
- Great! Sure.
- My father helped him with his career.
- He did?
How?
- Let's listen to this song.
- Michael...
Please, Michael. Tell me.
When Johnny was starting out, he was
signed to a personal service contract
with a big bandleader.
And as his career got better and better,
he wanted to get out of it.
Johnny is my father's godson.
My father went to see this bandleader.
He offered him 10,000 dollars
to let Johnny go,
but the bandleader said no.
So the next day my father went to see
him, but this time with Luca Brasi.
Within an hour,
he signed a release
for a certified cheque of 1,000 dollars.
- How did he do that?
- Made him an offer he couldn't refuse.
- What was that?
- Luca Brasi held a gun to his head,
and father said that either his brains or
his signature would be on the contract.
That's a true story.
That's my family, Kay. It's not me.
Beautiful!
I'll take care of it.
Tom...
I want you to find Santino.
Tell him to come to the office.
How are you, Fredo?
My brother Fredo,
this is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah. This is your friend?
I don't know what to do.
My voice is weak. It's weak.
Anyway, if I had this part in the picture,
it puts me right back on top again.
But this... man won't give it to me,
the head of the studio.
- What's his name?
- Woltz.
He won't give it to me,
and he says there's no chance.
Sonny?
- Sonny, are you in there?
- What?
The old man wants you.
One minute.
A month ago he bought the movie rights
to this book, a best-seller.
The main character
is a guy just like me.
I wouldn't even have to act.
Godfather, I don't know what to do.
You can act like a man!
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out a Hollywood
finocchio, that cries like a woman?
"What can I do? What can I do?"
What is that nonsense?
Ridiculous.
- You spend time with your family?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because a man who doesn't spend time
with his family can never be a real man.
You look terrible. I want you to eat.
Rest, and in a month this Hollywood
big shot will give you what you want.
It's too late, they start shooting
in a week.
I'm going to make him an offer
he can't refuse.
Just go outside and enjoy yourself,
and forget about all this nonsense.
- I want you to leave it all to me.
- All right.
- What time does my daughter leave?
- Soon, after they cut the cake.
Do we give your son-in-law
something important?
Never. Give him a living, but never
discuss the family business with him.
- What else?
- Virgil Sollozzo called.
- We'll have to see him next week.
- When you come back from California.
- When am I going to California?
- Tonight.
I want you to talk to this movie big shot
and settle this business for Johnny.
If there's nothing else, I'd like to go
to my daughter's wedding.
Carlo, we're going to take the picture.
Wait a minute.
No, Michael. Not me.
Okay, that's it. Just like that. Hold it!
- You need a little more heat on that arc.
- Start talking.
I was sent by a friend
of Johnny Fontane.
This friend would give
his friendship to Mr. Woltz,
if Mr. Woltz would grant us a favour.
Woltz is listening.
Give Johnny the part in that war film
you're starting next week.
And what favour would your friend
grant Mr. Woltz?
He could make your future union
problems disappear.
And one of your stars has just moved
from marijuana to heroin.
Are you trying to muscle me?
Listen, you son-of-a-bitch!
Let me lay it on the line. Johnny
Fontane will never get that movie!
No matter how many Dago Guinea
greaseballs come out of the woodwork!
- I'm German-Irish.
- Listen here, my Kraut-Mick friend.
- I'm going to make trouble for you!
- I'm a lawyer. I haven't threatened...
I know New York's big lawyers.
Who are you?
I have a special practice. I handle
one client. I'll wait for your call.
By the way, I admire your pictures
very much.
Check him out.
- It's really beautiful.
- Look at this.
- It used to decorate a king's palace.
- Very nice.
Why didn't you say
you work for Corleone?
I thought you were some cheap hustler
Johnny was running in.
- I only use his name when necessary.
- How's your drink?
- Fine.
- Now I'll show you something beautiful.
You do appreciate beauty, don't you?
There you are.
600,000 dollars on four hoofs.
I bet Russian czars never paid
that for a single horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not going to race him, though.
I'm going to put him out to stud.
Thanks, Tony.
Let's get something to eat.
Corleone is Johnny's godfather.
To the Italian people that's
a very sacred, close relationship.
I respect it. Tell him to ask me anything
else. This favour I can't give him.
He never asks a second favour
when he's been refused the first.
You don't understand. Johnny Fontane
never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him.
It'll make him a big star.
I'm going to run him out of the business,
and let me tell you why.
Johnny Fontane ruined one of Woltz
International's most valuable protégés.
We trained her for five years.
Singing, acting, dancing lessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands of dollars
on her, to make her a big star.
Let me be even more frank.
To show you that I'm not a hard-hearted
man. That it's not all dollars and cents.
She was beautiful.
She was young and innocent!
She's the greatest piece of ass I've had
and I've had them all over the world.
Then Johnny Fontane comes along with
his olive oil voice and Guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me look ridiculous!
And a man in my position can't afford
to be made to look ridiculous!
You get the hell out of here!
If that goombah tries any rough stuff,
tell him I'm no bandleader.
Yeah, I heard that story.
Thank you for dinner
and a very pleasant evening.
Maybe your car can take me
to the airport.
Mr. Corleone insists on hearing
bad news immediately.
- You're not too tired, are you, Tom?
- No, I slept on the plane.
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
Now...
Sollozzo is known as The Turk. He's
supposed to be very good with a knife,
but only in matters of business
with reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey,
where they grow poppy.
In Sicily he has plants to process them
into heroin.
He needs cash, he needs protection
from the police.
He'll give a piece of the action.
I don't know how much.
The Tattaglia family is behind him here.
They have to be in it for something.
- What about his prison record?
- One term in Italy, one here.
He's known as a top narcotics man.
- Santino, what do you think?
- A lot of money in that white powder.
Tom?
Yes. There's more money in narcotics
than anything else.
If we don't get into it, somebody else
will, maybe the five families.
With that money they can buy
more police and political power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have unions and gambling, and
that's great, but narcotics is the future.
If we don't get a piece of that action,
we risk everything in ten years' time.
So? What's your answer
going to be, Pop?
Don Corleone.
I need a man who has powerful friends.
I need a million dollars in cash.
I need those politicians that you carry
in your pocket, like nickels and dimes.
- What is the interest for my family?
- 30 percent.
In the first year your end should be
three, four million dollars.
And then it would go up.
And what is the interest
for the Tattaglia family?
My compliments.
I'll take care of them, out of my share.
So I receive 30 percent for finance,
political influence and legal protection?
That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider a million dollars in cash
just finance,
ti saluto, Don Corleone.
I said that I would see you, because
I heard you were a serious man,
to be treated with respect.
But, I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true, I have a lot of friends in politics.
They wouldn't be friendly long if I was
involved in drugs instead of gambling,
which they regard as a harmless vice,
but drugs is a dirty business.
It doesn't make any difference to me
what a man does for a living.
But your business is...
a little dangerous.
If you're worried about security,
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
- The Tattaglias would guarantee our...
- Wait a minute.
I have a sentimental weakness
for my children, and I spoil them.
They talk when they should listen.
But anyway...
Signor Sollozzo, my no is final. I wish to
congratulate you on your new business.
I know you'll do well, and good luck.
Especially since your interests
don't conflict with mine. Thank you.
Santino.
Come here.
What's the matter with you? Your brain
is going soft from playing with that girl.
Never tell anybody outside the family
what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom, what's this nonsense?
It's from Johnny.
He's starring in that new film.
- Take it away.
- Take it over there.
And...
...tell Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a little worried
about this Sollozzo fellow.
Find out what he's got
under his fingernails.
Go to the Tattaglias.
Make them think that you're not
too happy with our family
and find out what you can.
I got something for your mother
and for Sonny
and a tie for Freddy,
and Tom Hagen got the Reynolds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- Just you.
Andiamo, Fredo.
- Tell Paulie to get the car.
- Okay, Pop.
I'll have to get it myself.
Paulie called in sick this morning.
Paulie's a good kid.
I don't mind getting the car.
Buon Natale, caro. Grazie.
- Luca! I'm Bruno Tattaglia.
- I know.
You know who I am?
I know you.
You have been talking to the
Tattaglia family...right?
I think you and I can do business.
I need someone strong like you.
I heard you are not happy...
...with the Corleone family.
Want to join me?
What's in it for me?
$50,000 to start with.
Not bad!
Agreed?
Tom! Tom Hagen. Merry Christmas.
- Glad to see you. I want to talk to you.
- I haven't got time.
Make time, Consigliere. Get in the car.
What are you worried about? lf I wanted
to kill you, you'd be dead already.
Get in.
- Fredo, I'm going to buy some fruit.
- Okay, Pop.
Merry Christmas. I want some fruit.
Would you like me better
if I were a nun? Like in the story.
No.
- What if I were Ingrid Bergman?
- Now, that's a thought.
Michael.
No, I wouldn't like you better if you were
Ingrid Bergman. What's the matter?
They don't say if he's dead or alive.
- Sonny, it's Michael.
- Where have you been?
- Is he all right?
- We don't know yet.
There are all kinds of stories.
He was hit bad, Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
- Where have you been? I was worried.
- Didn't Tom tell you I called?
No. Look, come home, kid.
You should be with Mama, you hear?
Oh, my God.
Sonny!
Stay back there.
- Who is it?
- Open up, it's Clemenza.
There's more news about your old man.
Word is out that he's already dead.
- What's the matter with you?
- Take it easy!
- Where was Paulie?
- Sick. He's been sick all winter.
- How often?
- Only three, four times.
- Freddy didn't want a new bodyguard.
- Pick him up now.
I don't care how sick he is. Bring him
to my father's house right now.
- You want anyone sent over here?
- No. Go ahead.
I'm going to have a couple of our people
come over to the house.
- Hello?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
In three hours he'll be released
with our proposition.
Listen to what he has to say
before you do anything.
What's done is done. Don't lose that
famous temper of yours, Sonny.
I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in the muscle end
of the family, so don't be scared.
I want you to help the Corleones
and me.
We got him outside his office
about an hour after we picked you up.
Drink it.
It's up to you to make peace
between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot for my deal, wasn't he?
And you knew
it was the right thing to do.
- Sonny will come after you.
- That will be his first reaction, sure.
So you have to talk sense into him.
The Tattaglia family is behind me.
The other New York families will go
along with anything to prevent war.
Let's face it, with all due respect,
the Don - rest in peace - was slipping.
Ten years ago,
could I have gotten to him?
Well, now he's dead, Tom,
and nothing can bring him back.
You've got to talk to Sonny, to the
Caporegimes, Tessio, fat Clemenza.
It's good business, Tom.
I'll try. But even Sonny won't be able
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah, well...
Let me worry about Luca.
You just talk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
- I'll do my best.
- Good.
Now you can go.
I don't like violence, Tom.
I'm a businessman.
Blood is a big expense.
He's still alive.
They hit him with five shots,
and he's still alive!
That's bad luck for me, and bad luck
for you if you don't make that deal.
Your mother is at the hospital with
your father. Looks like he'll pull through.
It's a lot of bad blood. Sollozzo, Philip
Tattaglia, Bruno Tattaglia, Ramon...
- You gonna kill all those guys?
- Stay out of it.
If you get rid of Sollozzo,
everything falls into line.
What about Luca?
Sollozzo thinks he can control him.
If Luca sold out, we're in a lot of trouble.
- Has anyone been in touch with Luca?
- We've been trying all night.
- Hey, do me a favour...
- Luca never sleeps over with a broad.
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
What do we do if the old man dies?
If we lose the old man, we lose the
political contacts and half our strength.
The other New York families might
support Sollozzo to avoid a long war.
This is almost 1946.
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
...you make the deal.
- Easy to say. He's not your father.
- I'm as much a son as you or Mike.
What is it?
- Paulie, I told you to stay put.
- The guy at the gates has a package.
Tessio, go see what it is.
- Shall I stay?
- Yeah. Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- There's food. Are you hungry?
- No.
- A drink? Brandy will sweat it out.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
Take care of that son-of-a-bitch.
Paulie sold out the old man.
- Make that the first thing on your list.
- Understood.
Mickey, tomorrow, get some guys
and go to Luca's apartment.
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directly.
Hanging around the house on
the phone would be a big help.
Try Luca again.
- What's this?
- A Sicilian message.
It means Luca Brasi
sleeps with the fishes.
- I'm going.
- When will you be home?
Probably late.
- Don't forget the cannoli!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rocco, sit on the other side.
You block the rear-view mirror.
Sonny's running wild. He wants
to go to mattresses already.
We have to find a spot on the
West Side. Try 309 West 43rd Street.
- Know a good spot on the West Side?
- I'll think about it.
Think while you're driving.
I want to hit New York this month.
Watch the kids.
Paulie, go down 39th Street, pick up
18 mattresses and bring me the bill.
Yeah, all right.
Make sure they're clean, because
the guys will be there a long time.
- They're clean and exterminated.
- That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate! Watch out,
so we don't exterminate you!
Pull over. I've got to take a leak.