Leave the gun. Take the cannoli.
Hey, Mike! Hey, Mikey!
- Yeah.
- Phone call!
- Who is it?
- Some girl.
- Hello. Kay?
- How's your father?
He's going to make it.
I love you.
I love you!
- Michael?
- Yeah, I know.
- Tell me you love me.
- I can't talk.
Can't you say it?
I'll see you tonight.
Why don't you tell that nice girl
you love her?
I love you with all my heart. If I don't
see you again soon, I'm going to die!
Come and learn something. You might
have to cook for 20 guys some day.
You start with a little oil,
then fry some garlic.
Throw in some tomatoes, tomato paste,
fry it and make sure it doesn't stick.
You get it to a boil, you shove in
all your sausage and meatballs.
Add a little bit of wine.
And a little bit of sugar. That's my trick.
Cut the crap. I have more important
things for you. How's Paulie?
You won't see him no more.
- Where are you going?
- To the city.
- Send bodyguards with him.
- I'm going to the hospital...
He'll be all right. Sollozzo knows
he's a civilian.
- Be careful.
- Yes, sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
- I have to go.
- Can I go with you?
No, Kay. There will be detectives there,
people from the press.
I'll wait in the cab.
I don't want you to get involved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire, and I'll
call you at your parents' house.
- When will I see you again, Michael?
- I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
I'm Michael Corleone. This is my father.
What happened to the guards?
Your father had too many visitors.
They interfered with hospital service.
The police made them leave
about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 45620, please.
Nurse. Wait a minute. Stay here.
Sonny, I'm at the hospital.
I got here late, there's nobody here.
No Tessio's men, no detectives,
nobody. Papa's all alone.
- Don't panic.
- I won't panic.
I'm sorry, but you will have to leave.
We're going to move him to another
room. Can you disconnect the tubes?
- That's out of the question!
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here to kill him.
Do you understand?
Help me, please.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo, the baker.
- Remember me?
- Enzo.
You'd better go,
there's going to be trouble.
If there is trouble, I'll stay here to
help you. For your father.
Listen. Wait for me outside,
in front of the hospital, all right?
I'll be out in a minute.
Just lie here, Pop.
I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these. Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket, like you
have a gun. You'll be all right.
You did good.
I thought all you Guinea hoods
were locked up!
- Why isn't anyone guarding my father?
- You little punk!
Don't you tell me my business!
I pulled them off.
- Stay away from this hospital!
- Not until my father's room is guarded.
- Phil, take him in!
- The kid's clean, Captain.
- He's a war hero. He's never been...
- I said take him in!
- What's The Turk paying you?
- Take a hold of him. Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the Corleone's attorney. These men
are hired to protect Vito Corleone.
They're licensed to carry firearms.
If you interfere, you'll have to appear
before the judge and show cause.
Let him go.
- What's with all the new faces?
- We'll need them now.
After the hospital thing, Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno Tattaglia this morning.
Jesus Christ.
Looks like a fortress around here.
Tommasuccio! Hey... 1 00 buttonmen
on the street 24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair on his ass,
he's dead.
Mike, let me look at you.
You're beautiful, beautiful.
You're gorgeous.
The Turk wants to talk! Lmagine
the nerve of the son-of-a-bitch.
- He wants a meeting today.
- What did he say?
What did he say... He wants us to send
Michael to hear the proposition.
He promises that the deal
is too good to refuse.
- And Bruno Tattaglia?
- That's part of the deal.
- He cancels out what they did to Father.
- We should listen to them.
No more! Not this time, Consigliere.
No more meetings, discussions,
or Sollozzo tricks.
I want Sollozzo, or we go to war...
- The other families...
- They hand me Sollozzo!
This is business, not personal!
- They shot my father...
- Even that was business, not personal.
Then business will have to suffer.
Do me a favour.
No more advice on how to
patch things up. Just help me win.
I found out about Captain McCluskey,
who broke Mike's jaw.
He's definitely on Sollozzo's payroll,
and for big money.
McCluskey has agreed to be
The Turk's bodyguard.
So when Sollozzo is being guarded,
he's invulnerable.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York police captain.
All the families would come after you.
The Corleone family would be outcasts!
Even the old man's political protection
would run for cover.
Do me a favour.
Take this into consideration.
All right, we'll wait.
We can't wait. We can't wait.
No matter what Sollozzo says,
he's going to kill Pop.
That's the key for him.
We've got to get Sollozzo.
- Mike is right.
- Let me ask you something.
What about this McCluskey?
What do we do with this cop?
They want to have a meeting
with me, right?
It will be me, McCluskey and Sollozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be held.
We insist it's a public place.
A bar, a restaurant.
Some place where there are people,
so I feel safe.
They'll search me when I meet them,
right?
So I can't have a weapon on me.
But if Clemenza can figure out a way to
have a weapon planted there for me...
...then I'll kill them both.
Nice college boy. Didn't want to
get mixed up in the family business.
Now you want to shoot a police captain
because he slapped you?
This isn't like the army! You have to get
close and get their brains on your suit.
You're taking this very personal.
Tom, this is business
and he's taking it personal.
- Where does it say you can't kill a cop?
- Mikey...
I'm talking about a cop who's mixed up
in drugs, a dishonest cop.
A cop who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming.
That's a terrific story. We have
newspaper people on the payroll, right?
- They might like a story like that.
- They might.
It's not personal, Sonny.
It's strictly business.
It's as cold as they come. Impossible to
trace, so you don't worry about prints.
I put a special tape on the trigger
and the butt. Try it.
Is the trigger too tight?
My ears!
I left it noisy, so it scares away any
pain-in-the-ass innocent bystanders.
You've shot them both.
Now what do you do?
- Sit down, finish my dinner.
- Don't fool around.
Let your hand drop to your side
and let the gun slip out.
Everybody will still think you've got it.
They'll stare at your face,
so walk out fast, but don't run.
Don't look anybody in the eye,
but don't look away either.
They'll be scared stiff,
so don't worry about nothing.
You'll be all right. You'll take a vacation,
nobody knows where,
and we'll catch the hell.
- How bad do you think it will be?
- Pretty goddamn bad.
All the other families will probably
line up against us.
These things have to happen every five,
ten years. Gets rid of the bad blood.
Been ten years since the last one.
You have to stop them at the beginning.
Like they should have stopped Hitler in
Munich, not letting him get away with it.
You know, Mike, we were all proud
of you. Being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing. Not a hint. Absolutely nothing.
Even Sollozzo's people don't know
where the meeting will be held.
How much time do we have?
They're going to pick you up outside
Jack Dempsey's in an hour and a half.
- We could put a tail on them.
- Sollozzo would lose our ass.
- What about the negotiator?
- He's playing pinochle with my men.
- He's happy. They're letting him win.
- Too risky. Maybe we should call it off.
The negotiator plays cards
until Mike is back safe.
- He could blast whoever is in the car.
- They'll expect that.
Sollozzo might not even be
in the car, Sonny!
I'll get it.
Louis' restaurant in the Bronx.
- Is it reliable?
- My man in McCluskey's precinct.
A police captain is on call 24 hours
a day. He'll be there between 8 and 1 0.
- Anybody know this joint?
- Sure, I do. It's perfect for us.
A small family place, good food.
Everyone minds his business. Perfect.
They've got an old-fashioned toilet.
You know, the box and the chain thing.
We might be able to tape the gun
behind it.
All right. Mike, you go to the restaurant,
you eat, talk for a while, you relax.
Make them relax.
Then you go to take a leak. No, better
still, you ask permission to go.
Then you come back blasting.
Two shots in the head apiece.
I want somebody very good
to plant that gun.
I don't want him coming out
with just his dick.
- The gun will be there.
- You drive him and pick him up.
Let's move.
Did he tell you to drop the gun
right away?
Yeah, a million times.
Don't forget. Two shots apiece in
the head as soon as you come out.
How long do you think it will be
before I can come back?
At least a year.
I'll square it with Mom, that you're not
seeing her before you leave and...
I'll get a message to that girlfriend
when the time is right.
Take care.
Take care, Mike.
I'm glad you came. I hope we can
straighten everything out.
It's not the way I wanted things to go.
It should never have happened.
I want to straighten everything out.
I don't want my father bothered again.
I swear on my children
that he won't be, Mike.
But you have to keep an open mind
when we talk.
I hope you're not a hothead like Sonny.
You can't talk business with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry about the other night, Mike.
I've got to frisk you, so turn around.
On your knees, facing me.
I guess I'm getting too old for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's clean.
Going to Jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work, Lou.
- How's the food in this restaurant?
- Try the veal. It's the best in the city.
I'll have it.
- I'm going to speak Italian to Mikey.
- Go ahead.
What I want...
What's most important to me...
...is that I have a guarantee.
No more attempts on my father's life.
What guarantees can I give you?
I'm the hunted one!
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me, kid.
I'm not that clever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is it all right?
When you got to go, you got to go.
He's clean.
Don't take too long.
I've frisked a thousand punks.
Okay, you take over.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Pa. He doesn't know you yet.
- Hey, big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
- Okay.
"I hope you get well, Grandpa, and wish
I see you soon. Your grandson Frank."
Go with your mother.
Take them downstairs.
Go on, Carlo, you too.
Go on.
- What's the matter with you, Carlo?
- Shut up and set the table.
Since McCluskey's killing, the police
have cracked down on our operations.
And also the other families.
There's been a lot of bad blood.
They hit us, so we hit them back.
Through our newspaper contacts
we've been able to put out material
about McCluskey's link with Sollozzo
in the drug rackets.
So things are loosening up.
And I sent Fredo to Las Vegas, under
the protection of Don Francesco of L.A.
- I want him to rest.
- I'm going to learn the casino business.
Where's Michael?
It was Michael who killed Sollozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting to work
to bring him back.
Did you find out where that old pimp
Tattaglia is hiding? I want him now.
Sonny, things are starting to loosen up.
If you go after Tattaglia, all hell
will break loose. Pop can negotiate.
- He must get better first. I'll decide...
- War is costly. We can't do business.
- Neither can they. Don't worry about it!
- We can't afford a stalemate.
- No more stalemate. I'll kill the bastard!
- You're getting a great reputation!
Do as I say! If I had a Sicilian wartime
consigliere, I wouldn't be in this shape!
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
Ma made a little dinner. It's Sunday.
Niggers are having a good time
with our policy banks in Harlem.
Driving new Cadillacs,
paying 50 per cent on a bet.
That's because they've started
making big money.
Poppa never talked business
at the table.
- Shut up, Connie...
- Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
Don't interfere.
I'd like to talk to you after dinner.
I could do more for the family...
We don't discuss business at the table.
I kiss your hand, Don Tommasino.
Why are you so far
from the house?
You know I'm responsible to your
father for your life.
The bodyguards are here.
It's still dangerous...
We've heard from Santino
in New York...
Your enemies know you're here.
Did Santino say when
I can go back?
Not yet.
It's out of the question.
Where are you going now?
Take my car.
I want to walk.
Be careful.
Where have all the men gone?
They're all dead from vendettas.
There are the names of the dead.
Hey, hey, take me to the America, G.I.!
Clark Gable!
America! Take me to the America, G.I.!
Clark Gable, Rita Hayworth!
Mamma mia what a beauty.
I think you got hit
by the thunderbolt.
In Sicily women are more
dangerous than shotguns.
Did you have a good hunt?
You know all the girls
around here?
We saw some real beauties.
One of them struck our friend
like a thunderbolt.
She would tempt the devil himself.
Really put together.
Such hair, such mouth!
The girls around here are
beautiful... but virtuous.
This one had a purple dress...
And a purple ribbon in her hair.
A type more Greek than Italian.
Do you know her?
There's no girl like that
in this town.
My God, I understand!
What's wrong?
Let's go.
It's his daughter.
Tell him to come here.
Call him.
Fabrizio, you translate.
I apologise if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country.
I meant no disrespect
to you or your daughter.
I'm an American, hiding in Sicily.
My name is Michael Corleone.
There are people who'd pay a lot
of money for that information.
But then your daughter
would lose a father...
...instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter.
With your permission, and under
the supervision of your family.
With all respect.
Come to my house Sunday morning.
My name is Vitelli.
What's her name?
I'll knock you dizzy.
Save it for the library.
We've got to pick up my sister.
What's the matter?
- It was my fault!
- Where is he?
It was my fault. I hit him.
I started a fight with him.
I hit him, so he hit me...
I'm just going to get a doctor
to take a look at you.
Sonny, please don't do anything.
What's the matter with you?
What am I going to do?
Make that baby an orphan
before he's born?
You spic slobs still betting Yankees?
Tell them to stop taking in action.
We lost enough money last week.
Come here, come here!
If you touch my sister again, I'll kill you.
Hey! We weren't expecting you, Kay.
You should call.
Yes, I have. I've tried writing and calling.
- I want to reach Michael.
- Nobody knows where he is.
All we know is that he's all right.
- What was that?
- An accident, but nobody was hurt.
Tom, will you give this letter to Michael.
Please?
If I accepted that, a court could prove
I have knowledge of his whereabouts.
He'll get in touch with you.
I let my cab go, so can I call
another one, please?
Come on. Sorry.
- Hello?
- Is Carlo there?
- Who is this?
- A friend of Carlo.
Tell him that I can't make it tonight
until later.
Bitch!
- Dinner's on the table.
- I'm not hungry.
- The food is getting cold.
- I'll eat out later.
You just told me to make you dinner!
She has a filthy mouth, this Guinea brat.
That's it, break it all, you spoiled
Guinea brat. Break it all!
Why don't you bring your whore
home for dinner?
Maybe I will.
- Clean it up!
- Like hell I will!
You skinny, spoiled brat.
Clean it up! Clean it up!
Clean it up! I said, clean it up!
Clean it up!
Clean it up. Clean that up, you...
Clean it!
Clean it up! Yeah, kill me.
Be a murderer, like your father!
- All you Corleones are murderers!
- I hate you!
Come on, kill me!