When I meet with the Tattaglia
people, should I insist...
that all these drug middlemen
have clean records?
Mention it.
Don't insist.
Barzini is a man who'll know that
without being told.
You mean Tattaglia.
Tattaglia's a pimp.
He never could've
outfought Santino.
But I didn't know until this day
that it was...
Barzini all along.
Come on, Nancy.
Keep together, everyone.
Brian?
All right.
How long have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that, I think.
It's good to see you, Kay.
Hi, Miss Adams!
I'm working for my father now.
He's been sick.
Very sick.
But you're not like him.
I thought you weren't going
to become a man like your father.
That's what you told me.
My father's no different
than any other powerful man.
Any man who's responsible
for other people.
Like a senator or a president.
- Do you know how naive you sound?
- Why?
Senators and presidents
don't have men killed.
Who's being naive?
My father's way
of doing things is over.
It's finished.
Even he knows that.
I mean, in five years
the Corleone family...
is going to be
completely legitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can tell you
about my business.
Why did you come here?
Why?
What do you want with me
after all this time...
without even calling or writing?
I came here because I need you.
- Because I care for you.
- Please stop it.
Because I want you to marry me.
- It's too late.
- Please.
I'll do anything you ask to make up
for what's happened to us.
Because that's important.
Because what's important is that...
we have each other.
That we have a life together.
That we have children-
our children.
I need you...
and I love you.
Barzini's people
chisel my territory...
and we do nothing about it.
Soon, there won't be one place
in Brooklyn I can hang my hat.
- Just be patient.
- I'm not askin' you for help.
- Just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
We gotta protect ourselves.
Give me a chance to recruit
some new men.
No.
I don't wanna give Barzini
an excuse to start fighting.
Mike, you're wrong.
Don Corleone,
you once said the day would come...
when Tessio and me
could form our own family.
Till today,
I would never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
Well, Michael is now
head of the family...
and if he gives his permission,
then you have my blessing.
After we make the move to Nevada...
you can break off from the Corleone
family and go on your own.
- After we make the move to Nevada.
- How long will that be?
Six months.
Forgive me, Godfather,
but with you gone...
me and Pete'll come under
Barzini's thumb sooner or later.
And I hate that goddamn Barzini.
In six months' time, there won't be
nothing left to build on.
- You have faith in my judgment?
- Yes.
- Do I have your loyalty?
- Always, Godfather.
Then be a friend to Michael...
and do as he says.
There are things being negotiated
that are gonna solve...
all your problems
and answer all your questions.
That's all I can tell you now.
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there,
you're gonna be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen's no longer consigliere.
He's gonna be our lawyer in Vegas.
That's no reflection on Tom,
but that's the way I want it.
Besides, if I ever need help...
who's a better consigliere
than my father?
That's it.
- Thank you, Papa.
- I'm happy for you, Carlo.
Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere.
Things may get rough
with the move we're trying.
I advised Michael.
I never thought
you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a bad Don...
rest in peace.
Michael has all my confidence,
as you do.
But there are reasons why
you must have no part...
of what is going to happen.
Maybe I could help.
You're out.
I can't get over the way
your face looks.
It really looks good.
This doctor did some job.
Who talked you into it, Kay?
Hey, hey, wait.
Leave them out here.
We'll deal with them later.
He's tired.
He wants to clean up.
Now, let me open the door.
Hello, Mike.
Welcome to Las Vegas.
All for you, kid.
It was all his idea, right?
- Well, your brother, Freddy-
- It was- Girls?
I'll be right back.
You keep them occupied.
That a boy.
Anything you want, kid.
Who are the girls?
That's for you to find out.
Get rid of them.
- Hey, Mike-
- I'm here on business.
I leave tomorrow.
Now, get rid of them. I'm tired.
Get rid of the band too.
Hey, just take off.
Come on. Let's go.
Hey, that's it.
Angelo, that's it.
Let's go.
Hey, come on!
Scram!
Come on, honey. Let's go.
I don't know, Johnny.
I don't know what the hell's
the matter with him.
It's all right, Freddy.
I don't know.
He's tired, he's hot.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He said he had some business.
He said give him a call...
when the party started.
Well, give him a call.
- Johnny, how are you?
- Hello. Nice to see you again.
- We're all proud of you.
- Thanks, Mike.
Sit down, Johnny.
I want to talk to you.
- The Don's proud of you too.
- I owe it all to him.
Well, he knows
how grateful you are.
That's why he'd like to ask
a favor of you.
Mike, what can I do?
The Corleone family is thinking
of giving up all its interests...
in the olive oil business,
settling out here.
Now, Moe Greene will sell us
his share of the casino and hotel...
so it can be completely owned
by the family.
Mike, are you sure about that?
Moe loves the business. He never
said nothin' to me about sellin'.
I'll make him an offer
he can't refuse.
See, Johnny...
we figure that entertainment
will be a big factor...
in drawing gamblers to the casino.
We hope you'll sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of
your friends in the movies...
to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure, Mike.
I'll do anything for my godfather.
You know that.
Good.
Hey, Mike.
Hello, fellas.
Everybody's here. Freddy, Tom.
Good to see you, Mike.
- How are you, Moe?
- You got everything you want?
The chef cooked for you special, the
dancers will kick your tongue out...
and your credit is good.
Draw chips for everybody in the room
so they can play on the house.
My credit good enough
to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino.
The hotel.
The Corleone family
wants to buy you out.
wants to buy me out?
No, I buy you out.
You don't buy me out.
Your casino loses money.
Maybe we can do better.
You think I'm skimming
off the top?
You're unlucky.
You goddamn guineas
really make me laugh.
I do you a favor and take Freddy in
when you're having a bad time.
- Then you try to push me out!
- Wait a minute.
You took Freddy in because
the Corleone family...
bankrolled your casino because
the Molinari family...
on the coast
guaranteed his safety.
Now, we're talkin' business.
Let's talk business.
First of all, you're all done.
The Corleone family don't have
that kind of muscle anymore.
The Godfather's sick. You're
getting chased out of New York...
by Barzini and the other families.
You think you can come to my hotel
and take over?
I talked to Barzini.
I can make a deal with him
and still keep my hotel.
Is that why you slapped
my brother around in public?
That was nothin'.
Moe didn't mean nothin' by that.
Sure he flies off the handle
once in a while...
but Moe and me,
we're good friends, right?
I got a business to run.
I gotta kick asses sometimes
to make it run right.
We had a little argument,
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktail waitresses
two at a time!
Players couldn't get a drink.
What's wrong with you?
I leave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son of a bitch.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Moe Greene.
I made my bones when you were
going out with cheerleaders.
Wait a minute.
I got an idea.
Tom, you're the consigliere.
You can talk to the Don.
- You can explain-
- Just a minute.
The Don is semiretired. Mike is
in charge of the business now.
If you have anything to say,
say it to Michael.
You don't come to Las Vegas
and talk to Moe Greene like that!
You're my older brother,
and I love you.
But don't ever take sides
with anyone...
against the family again...
ever.
I have to see my father
and his people.
Have dinner without me.
This weekend we'll go out.
We'll go to the city.
We'll see a show and have dinner.
I promise.
Your sister wants
to ask you something.
- Let her ask.
- She's afraid to.
Connie and Carlo want you to be
godfather to their little boy.
- We'll see.
- Will you?
Let me think about it.
Come on.
So...
Barzini will move
against you first.
He'll set up a meeting with
someone that you absolutely trust...
guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting,
you'll be assassinated.
I like to drink wine
more than I used to.
Anyway, I'm drinking more.
It's good for you, Pop.
I don't know.
Your wife and children,
are you happy with them?
Very happy.
That's good.
I hope you don't mind
the way I-
I keep going over
this Barzini business.
No, not at all.
It's an old habit.
I spent my life
tryin' not to be careless.
Women and children can be careless,
but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
You know, he looks
more like you every day.
He's smarter than I am.
Three years old,
he can read the funny papers.
He reads the funny papers.
I want you to arrange
to have a telephone man...
check all the calls that go
in and out of here.
- I did it already.
- Could be anyone.
- I took care of that.
- That's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handle it.
I told you I can handle it,
I knew that Santino was gonna
have to go through all this...
and Fredo-
Well...
Fredo was-
But I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whole life-
I don't apologize-
to take care of my family...
and I refused to be a fool...
dancing on a string
held by all those big shots.
I don't apologize. That's my life.
But I thought that-
that when it was your time...
you would be the one
to hold the strings.
Senator Corleone.
Governor Corleone.
Something.
Another pezzonovante.
Just wasn't enough time.
Wasn't enough time.
We'll get there, Pop.
We'll get there.
Listen, whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting...
he's the traitor.
Don't forget that.
Put it over the tree.
- Can I water these?
- Yeah.
That's fine.
Over here.
Be careful.
You're spilling it.
Anthony, come here.
Go ahead. That's right.
We'll put it right there.
I'll show you something.
Come here.
Now, you stand there.
Give me an orange!
That's a new trick.
You run in there.
Run in there.
- Where are you?
- Who?
Ouch!
Mike, can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten
any of our problems out.
- You talked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security...
on my territory.
All right?
- All right.
Do you know how
they're gonna come at you?
They're arranging a meeting
in Brooklyn.
Tessio's ground...
where I'll be safe.
I always thought it would've been
Clemenza, not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was always smarter.
But I'm gonna wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather
to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet
with Don Barzini...
and Tattaglia...
all the heads
of the five families.
Michael, do you believe in God,
the Father Almighty...
- creator of Heaven and Earth?
- I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ,
His only Son, our Lord?
I do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church?
I do.
Michael Francis Rizzi,
do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
Michael Rizzi,
will you be baptized?
I will.
Michael Rizzi, go in peace.
And may the Lord be with you.
Amen.
- Carlo.
- What?
Can't go to Vegas.
Something's come up.
Everybody's gonna have to leave
without us.
- It's our first vacation together.
- Connie, please.
- What do you wanna do?
- Go back to the house.
Wait for my call.
It's important.
I'll only be a couple of days.
Have a nice trip, Mama.
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
I hope Mike can get us
a good deal tonight.
I'm sure he will.
Sal, Tom, the boss says
he'll come in a separate car.
He says for you two
to go on ahead.
He can't do that.
It screws up all my arrangements.
- That's what he said.
- I can't go either, Sal.
Tell Mike it was only business.
I always liked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me, Sal.
Can you get me off the hook?
- For old times' sake.
- Can't do it, Sally.
You have to answer
for Santino, Carlo.
You got it all wrong.
You fingered Sonny
for the Barzini people.
That little farce you played
with my sister.
Did you think that could fool
a Corleone?
I'm innocent.
I swear on the kids.
- Please, don't do this to me.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me, please.
Barzini's dead.
So is Phillip Tattaglia...
Moe Greene...
Strachi...
Cuneo.
Today I settle all family business,
so don't tell me you're innocent.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid.
You think I'd make my sister
a widow?
I'm godfather to your son.
Go ahead, drink.
Drink.
No, you're out
of the family business.
That's your punishment.
You're finished.
I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
I want you to stay there.
Understand?
Only don't tell me
you're innocent...
because it insults my intelligence.
It makes me very angry.
Now, who approached you?
Tattaglia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting for you
outside to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife,
tell her what flight you're on.
- Please, can I-
- Get out of my sight.
Hello, Carlo.
Will you stop crying?
What are you trying to tell me?
- I'm telling you you're wrong.
- Mama, please!
Where is he?
Michael, you lousy bastard!
You killed my husband!
You waited until Papa died
so nobody could stop you...
and then you killed him!
You blamed him for Sonny.
You always did. Everybody did.
But you never thought about me!
You never gave a damn about me!
Now what am I gonna do?
Why do you think
he kept Carlo at the mall?
All the time he knew
he was gonna kill him.
And you stood godfather
to our baby.
You lousy, coldhearted bastard.
Want to know how many men
he had killed with Carlo?
Read the papers!
That's your husband!
Take her upstairs.
- Get her a doctor.
- Oh, God!
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
Is it true?
Don't ask me about my business.
- Is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business.
Enough!
All right.
This one time.
This one time, I'll let you
ask me about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
I guess we both need a drink, huh?
Come on.
Don Corleone.