Get out of here!
- I hate you!
- Now I'll kill you.
You Guinea brat. Get out of here!
Connie, what's the matter?
I can't hear you.
Connie, talk louder. The baby's crying.
Santino, I can't understand.
I don't know.
Yeah, Connie.
You wait there.
No, you just wait there.
Son-of-a-bitch.
- Son-of-a-bitch!
- What's the matter?
Open the goddamn gate!
Get off your ass.
Sonny!
- Sonny.
- Get out of here!
Go after him, go on!
Son-of-a-bitch. Come on!
Give me a drop.
My wife is crying upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliere of mine,
tell your Don what everyone
seems to know.
I didn't tell Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake you
and tell you.
But you needed a drink first.
Yeah.
Well, now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
He's dead.
I want no inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
...with the heads of the five families.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
I need him now.
This is Tom Hagen. I'm calling for
Vito Corleone, at his request.
You owe your Don a service.
He has no doubt that you will repay it.
He will be at your funeral parlour
in one hour. Be there to greet him.
Well, my friend, are you ready
to do me this service?
Yes. What do you want me to do?
I want you to use all your powers
and all your skills.
I don't want his mother
to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
It's safer to teach you English!
I know English...
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday,
Wednesday, Friday, Sunday, Saturday.
Greetings, Don Tommasino.
How are things in Palermo?
Michael is teaching me to
drive... watch, I'll show you.
How are things in Palermo?
Young people don't respect
anything any more...
times are changing for the worse.
This place has become
too dangerous for you.
I want you to move to a villa
near Siracusa... right now.
What's wrong?
Bad news from America.
Your brother, Santino,
they killed him.
Let's go... you promised.
Get the car.
Are you driving yourself, Boss?
Is your wife coming with you?
No, take her to her father's house
until things are safe.
Okay, anything you say.
Calo, where is Apollonia?
She's going to surprise you.
She wants to drive.
She'll make a good American wife.
Wait, I'll get the baggage.
Fabrizio!
Where are you going?
Wait there! I'll drive to you.
No, Apollonia!
Don Barzini, I want to thank you
for helping me organise this meeting,
and the other heads of the five families
from New York and New Jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx,
and from Brooklyn...
...Philip Tattaglia.
And from Staten Island
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And the other associates that came as
far as from California and Kansas City
and all the other territories
of the country. Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate, so unnecessary.
Tattaglia lost a son, and I lost a son.
We're quits. And if Tattaglia agrees,
then I'm willing to let things go on
as before.
We're grateful to Don Corleone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him as a man of his word.
A modest man who listens to reason.
Yes, Don Barzini. He's too modest.
He had all the judges and politicians
in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse
an accommodation?
All of you know me.
When did I ever refuse,
except one time? And why?
Because I believe this drug business
will destroy us in the years to come.
It's not like gambling or liquor
or even women,
which is something that most people
want, but is forbidden by the Church.
Even the police that have helped us in
the past with gambling and other things
are going to refuse to help us
when it comes to narcotics.
I believed that then...
and I believe that now.
Times have changed.
It's not like the old days,
when we could do anything we wanted.
A refusal is not the act of a friend.
If Don Corleone had all the judges and
politicians, then he must share them
or let others use them. He must let us
draw the water from the well.
Certainly he can present a bill
for such services.
After all, we're not communists.
I also don't believe in drugs.
For years I paid my people extra, so
they wouldn't do that kind of business.
Somebody says to them
"I have powders."
"If you put up 3-4,000 dollar investment,
we can make 50,000 distributing."
They can't resist. I want to control it
as a business, keep it respectable.
I don't want it near schools,
I don't want it sold to children.
That's an infàmia.
In my city we would keep the traffic
to the coloured.
They're animals,
so let them lose their souls.
I hoped that we could come here
and reason together.
And I'm willing to do whatever is
necessary to find a peaceful solution.
We are agreed. The traffic in drugs
will be permitted, but controlled.
Don Corleone will give us protection
in the east, and there will be peace.
I must have strict assurance
from Corleone.
As time goes by and his position
becomes stronger,
will he attempt any individual vendetta?
We are all reasonable men.
We don't have to give assurances.
You talk about vengeance.
Will vengeance bring your son
back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forgo the vengeance of my son.
But I have selfish reasons.
My youngest son was forced
to leave this country...
...because of this Sollozzo business.
And I have to make arrangements
to bring him back here safely.
Cleared of all these false charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
If an unlucky accident should befall him,
if he should be shot by a police officer,
or if he should hang himself
in his jail cell,
or if he's struck by a bolt of lightning,
then I'm going to blame
some of the people in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But, that aside...
...let me say that I swear...
...on the souls of my grandchildren,
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.
Should I insist that all of Tattaglia's
drug middlemen have clean records?
Mention it. Don't insist.
- Barzini will know without being told.
- You mean Tattaglia.
Tattaglia's a pimp. He could never
have outfought Santino.
But I didn't know until this day
that it was Barzini all along.
Come on, Nancy.
Keep together, everyone. Brian.
Okay, all right.
How long have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that, I think.
It's good to see you, Kay.
I'm working for my father now, Kay.
He's been sick. Very sick.
But you're not like him. You told me you
weren't going to become like your father.
My father is no different
than any other powerful man.
Any man who's responsible
for other people.
Like a senator or president.
- How naive you sound.
- Why?
They don't have men killed.
Who's being naive, Kay?
My father's way of doing things is over.
Even he knows that.
In five years the Corleone family
is going to be completely legitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can tell you
about my business. Kay...
Michael, why did you come here? Why?
What do you want with me after all
this time? I've been calling and writing.
I came because I need you.
I care for you.
- Please stop it, Michael.
- Because... I want you to marry me.
- It's too late.
- Please, Kay...
I'll do anything you ask to make up for
what's happened to us.
Because that's important, Kay.
Because what's important is that...
...we have each other.
That we have a life together.
That we have children. Our children.
Kay, I need you.
And I love you.
Barzini's people chisel my territory
and we do nothing about it!
- Soon I'll have no place to hang my hat!
- Be patient.
I'm not asking for help.
Just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
- We must protect ourselves.
- Let me recruit some new men.
- No.
- Barzini would get an excuse to fight.
- Mike, you're wrong.
Don Corleone...
You once said that one day Tessio
and me could form our own family.
Till today I would never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
Michael is now head of the family.
If he gives his permission,
then you have my blessing.
After we make the move to Nevada
you can leave the Corleone family
and go on your own.
- How long will that be?
- Six months.
Forgive me, but with you gone, me and
Pete will come under Barzini's thumb.
I hate that Barzini. In six months' time
there will be nothing left to build on.
- Do you have faith in my judgement?
- Yes.
- Do I have your loyalty?
- Always, Godfather.
Then be a friend to Michael.
Do as he says.
Things are negotiated that'll solve your
problems and answer your questions.
That's all I can tell you now.
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there,
you'll be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen is no longer consigliere.
He'll be our lawyer in Vegas.
That's no reflection on Tom,
just how I want it.
If I ever need help, who's a better
consigliere than my father? That's it.
- Thank you, Poppa.
- I'm happy for you, Carlo.
Mike... Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere, Tom.
Things may get rough with the move.
Tom.
I advised Michael. I never thought
you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a bad Don,
rest in peace.
Michael has all my confidence,
just as you do.
But there are reasons why you must
have no part in what is going to happen.
- Maybe I could help.
- You're out, Tom.
I can't get over the way your face looks.
So good!
This doctor did some job. Did Kay
talk you into it? Hey, hey, hey!
Leave them out here.
He's tired and wants to clean up.
Let me open the door, all right?
- Hello, Mike! Welcome to Las Vegas!
- All for you, kid! It's all his idea.
- Your brother Freddy.
- Girls?
I'll be right back. Keep them occupied.
- Anything you want, kid, anything.
- Who are the girls?
- That's for you to find out.
- Get rid of them, Fredo.
- Hey, Mike...
- I'm here on business. Get rid of them.
I'm tired. Get rid of the band too.
Hey, take off. Take off. Let's go.
Hey, that's it. Hey, Angelo.
Hey, come on! Scram!
Come on, honey. I don't know
what's the matter with him, Johnny.
Sorry.
I don't know. He's tired.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He had some business. He said to
give him a call when the party started.
Well, give him a call.
- Johnny, how are you?
- Nice to see you, Mike.
- We're proud of you.
- Thanks.
Sit down, I want to talk to you.
The Don is proud too.
Well, I owe it all to him.
He knows how grateful you are. That's
why he'd like to ask a favour of you.
Mike, what can I do?
We're thinking of giving up our interests
in the olive oil business and settle here.
Moe will sell us his share of the casino
and the hotel, so we'll own all of it. Tom!
Are you sure? Moe loves the business.
He never said nothing about selling.
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
See, Johnny...
We figure that entertainment
would draw gamblers to the casino.
We hope you'll sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of your friends
in the movies to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure, Mike. I'll do anything
for my godfather.
Good.
Hey, Mike! Hello, fellows.
Everybody's here. Freddy, Tom.
- Good to see you.
- How are you, Moe?
Have everything? Specially prepared
food, the best dancers, and good credit.
Draw chips for everybody,
so they can play on the house.
Is my credit good enough
to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino, the hotel. The
Corleone family wants to buy you out.
The Corleone family wants to
buy me out? No, I buy you out.
Your casino loses money.
We can do better.
- You think I'm skimming off the top?
- You're unlucky.
You Guineas make me laugh.
I took Freddy in when you had a bad
time, and now you try to push me out!
You did that because we bankrolled
your casino
and the Molinari family guaranteed
his safety. Let's talk business.
Yes. First of all, you're all done. You
don't have that kind of muscle anymore.
The Godfather is sick. You're getting
chased out of New York by the others.
Do you think you can come to my hotel
and take over?
I talked to Barzini. I can make a deal
with him and still keep my hotel!
Is that why you slapped my brother
around in public?
That was nothing, Mike.
Moe didn't mean nothing by that.
He flies off the handle sometimes,
but we're good friends.
I have a business to run.
I've got to kick asses sometimes.
We had an argument,
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktail waitresses!
Players couldn't get a drink.
What's wrong with you?
I leave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son-of-a-bitch!
I'm Moe Greene! I made my bones
when you were out with cheerleaders.
Wait a minute, Moe. I have an idea.
Tom, you're the consigliere.
Talk to the Don...
Just a minute. Don is semi-retired and
Mike is in charge of the family business.
If you have anything to say,
say it to Michael.
Mike, you don't come to Las Vegas and
talk to a man like Moe Greene like that!
Fredo...
You're my older brother, and I love you.
But don't ever take sides with anyone
against the family again.
I have to see my father and his people,
so have dinner without me.
This weekend we'll go out. We'll go to
the city, see a show and have dinner.
Your sister wants to ask you something.
- Let her ask.
- She's afraid to.
They want you to be godfather
to their boy.
- We'll see.
- Will you?
Let me think about it. Come on.
Barzini will move against you first.
He'll set up a meeting with someone
you absolutely trust.
Guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting
you'll be assassinated.
I like to drink wine more than I used to.
- Anyway, I'm drinking more.
- It's good for you, Pop.
I don't know.
Are you happy with your wife
and children?
- Very happy.
- That's good.
I hope you don't mind the way I keep
going over this Barzini business.
- No, not at all.
- It's an old habit.
I spend my life trying not to be careless.
Women and children can be careless,
but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
He looks more like you every day.
He's smarter than I am. He's three
and can read the funny papers.
Read the funny papers.
I want you to arrange for a telephone
man to check all in- And out-going calls.
- I did it already. I took care of that, Pop.
- That's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handle it. I told you I can handle it,
so I'll handle it.
I knew that Santino would have to
go through all this.
And Fredo...
Fredo was, well...
But I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whole life. I don't apologise
for taking care of my family.
And I refused to be a fool,
dancing on a string
held by all those big shots.
I don't apologise. That's my life,
but I thought that...
...that when it was your time, you would
be the one to hold the strings.
Senator Corleone. Governor Corleone.
Something.
Another pezzo da novanta.
Well...
Just wasn't enough time, Michael.
Wasn't enough time.
We'll get there, Pop. We'll get there.
Now listen, whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting,
he's the traitor. Don't forget that.
Can I hold it, please?
- Can I water these?
- Yes, go ahead.
Over here, over here.
Be careful. You're spilling it.
Antony!
Come here, come here.
That's it. We'll put it right there.
I'll show you something. Come here.
Stand there.
Give me an orange!
That's a new trick.
You run in there. Run in there.
Where are you?
Mike, can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten out
any of our problems.
- You talked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security. On my territory.
- All right?
- All right.
Do you know how they're going to
come at you?
They're arranging a meeting
in Brooklyn. Tessio's ground.
Where I'll be safe.
I always thought it would be
Clemenza, not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was always smarter.
But I'm going to wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather
to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet with Don Barzini
and Tattaglia.
All the heads of the five families.
Michael, do you believe in God, the
Father, Creator of Heaven and Earth?
I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ,
His only Son, our Lord?
I do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church?
I do.
Michael Francis Rizzi,
do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
Oh, God!
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
Michael Rizzi, will you be baptised?
I will.
Michael Rizzi, go in peace, and may
the Lord be with you. Amen.
Kay!
Kiss your godfather.
Can't go to Vegas. Something's come
up. Everybody has to leave without us.
- Mike, it's our first vacation!
- Connie, please.
Go back to the house, wait for my call.
It's important.
I'll only be a couple of days.
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
- I hope Mike can get us a good deal.
- I'm sure he will.
Sal, Tom, the boss says he'll come in a
separate car, so you two go on ahead.
- That screws up my arrangements.
- That's what he said.
I can't go either, Sal.
Tell Mike it was only business.
I always liked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me, Sal.
Tom, can you get me off the hook?
- For old times' sake?
- Can't do it, Sally.
You have to answer for Santino, Carlo.
- Mike, you got it all wrong.
- You fingered Sonny for Barzini.
That little farce you played
with my sister.
- You think that could fool a Corleone?
- I'm innocent. I swear on the kids.
- Please, don't do this.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me, please.
Barzini is dead.
So is Philip Tattaglia.
Moe Greene.
Strachi. Cuneo.
Today I settle all family business,
so don't tell me you're innocent, Carlo.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid, Carlo. Do you think
I'd make my sister a widow?
I'm godfather to your son, Carlo.
Go ahead, drink, drink.
No, you're out of the family business.
That's your punishment.
You're finished.
I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
Tom.
I want you to stay there. Understand?
Only don't tell me you're innocent.
Because it insults my intelligence.
Makes me very angry.
Who approached you?
Tattaglia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting outside
to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife and tell her
what flight you're on.
- Mike...
- Get out of my sight.
Hello, Carlo.
- I'm trying to tell you...
- Mama, please!
Michael!
- What is it?
- Where is he?
Michael, you lousy bastard!
You killed my husband.
You waited until Papa died,
so nobody could stop you.
You blamed him for Sonny.
Everybody did.
But you never thought about me!
Now what are we going to do?
Connie.
Why do you think he kept Carlo at the
Mall? He knew he was going to kill him.
And you stood godfather to our baby.
You lousy cold-hearted bastard!
Want to know how many men he had
killed with Carlo? Read the papers!
That's your husband,
that's your husband!
No! No, no...
Take her upstairs. Get her a doctor.
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
Michael, is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business, Kay.
- Is it true?
Don't ask me about my business.
Enough!
All right.
This one time.
This one time I'll let you ask me
about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
No.
I guess we both need a drink. Come on.
Don Corleone.