I believe in America.
America has made my fortune...
and I raised my daughter
in the American fashion.
I give her freedom,
but I taught her...
never to dishonor her family.
She found a boyfriend.
Not an Italian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out late.
I didn't protest.
Two months ago,
he took her for a drive...
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey...
and then they tried
to take advantage of her.
She resisted.
She kept her honor.
So they beat her
like an animal.
When I went to the hospital,
her nose was broken...
her jaw was shattered...
held together by wire.
She couldn't even weep
because of the pain.
But I wept.
Why did I weep?
She was the light of my life.
Beautiful girl.
Now she will never
be beautiful again.
Sorry.
I went to the police
like a good American.
These two boys
were brought to trial.
A judge sentence them
to three years in prison...
and suspend their sentence.
Suspended sentence.
They went free that very day.
I stood in the courtroom
like a fool.
And those two bastard,
they smiled at me.
Then I said to my wife,
" For justice...
we must go to Don Corleone. "
Why did you go to the police?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me?
Tell me anything,
but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
We've known each other many years,
but this is the first time...
you ever came to me
for counsel or for help.
I can't remember the last time
that you invited me...
to your house
for a cup of coffee...
even though my wife
is godmother to your only child.
But let's be frank.
You never wanted my friendship...
and you were afraid
to be in my debt.
I didn't want
to get into trouble.
I understand.
You found paradise in America.
You had a good trade,
made a good living.
Police protected you,
and there were courts of law.
So you didn't need
a friend like me.
But now you come to me
and you say...
"Don Corleone, give me justice. "
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship.
You don't even think
to call me "Godfather. "
Instead, you come
into my house...
on the day my daughter
is to be married...
and you ask me to do murder
for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice.
Your daughter is still alive.
They must suffer then
as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonasera.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfully?
If you’d come to me
in friendship...
then the scum
that ruined your daughter...
would be suffering
this very day.
And if, by chance...
an honest man like yourself
should make enemies...
then they would become
my enemies.
And then they would fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather.
Good.
Someday, and that day
may never come...
I'll call upon you
to do a service for me.
But until that day...
accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
Grazie, Godfather.
Give this to Clemenza.
I want reliable people...
people that aren't
going to be carried away.
I mean, we're not murderers...
in spite of what
this undertaker says.
- Where's Michael?
- What? Don't worry.
It's early. He'll be here.
We're not taking it.
We're not taking the picture
without Michael.
- What's the matter, Sonny?
- It's Michael.
Don Barzini.
Hey, Paulie!
Let me have some wine.
Paulie! More wine.
Scusi, please.
You look "terrif" on the floor.
What are you,
a dance judge or something?
Go take a walk around
the neighborhood. Do your job.
Sandra, come on. Do me a favor.
Watch the kids.
- Don't let 'em run wild.
- You watch yourself, all right?
Twenty or thirty grand.
In small bills, cash.
In that little silk purse.
If this was
somebody else's wedding.
Hey, Paulie!
I got two gobbagool...
gabagol and a prosciutto.
Stupid jerk!
Hey, what's the matter?
Have to go back to work.
It's part of the wedding.
No Sicilian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your home-
Get outta here.
This is a private party.
Go on.
What is it?
Hey, my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI
don't respect nothin'.
Hey, come here, come here.
Come here!
There.
But towards the end
he was paroled...
to help with
the American war effort.
For the last six months, he's been
working at my pastry shop.
Nazorine, my friend,
what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over...
this boy, Enzo, they want
to repatriate him back to Italy.
Godfather, I have a daughter.
See, she and Enzo-
You want Enzo to stay
in this country...
and you want your daughter
to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr. Hagen. Thank you.
And wait till you see
the beautiful wedding cake...
I made for your daughter.
Like this, with the bride
and the groom and-
- Who should I give this job to?
- Not to our paisan.
Give it to a Jew congressman
in another district.
Who else is on the list?
Hey, Michael.
How are you?
Hello.
He's not on the list,
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this necessary?
He didn't expect to be invited
to the wedding...
so he wanted to thank you.
All right.
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your home...
on the wedding day
of your daughter.
And may their first child
be a masculine child.
- Don-
- Michael?
Don Corleone-
That man over there
is talking to himself.
See that scary guy over there?
He's a very scary guy.
Who is he?
What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi...
and he helps my father out
sometimes.
Wait a minute.
He's coming over here.
You look terrific!
My brother Tom Hagen.
This is Kay Adams.
How do you do?
Nice to meet you.
Your father's
been asking for you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
I'll be there.
If he's your brother,
why does he have a different name?
When my brother Sonny
was a kid...
he found Tom Hagen in the street,
and he had no home.
So my father took him in...
and he's been with us ever since.
He's a good lawyer.
Not a Sicilian, but...
I think
he's gonna be consigliere.
- What's that?
- That's...
like a counselor, an advisor.
Very important to the family.
You like your lasagna?
Don Corleone,
I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding...
on the day
of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope
that their first child...
be a masculine child.
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
For your daughter's
bridal purse.
Thank you, Luca,
my most valued friend.
Don Corleone,
I'm gonna leave you now...
because I know you are busy.
Thank you.
Senator Cauly apologized
for not coming personally...
but said you'd understand.
Also some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
Johnny!
I love you.
Hey, Johnny, look over here!
He came all the way from California
to come to the wedding.
- I told you he was going to come.
- It's been two years.
- He's probably in trouble again.
- He's a good godson.
Sing a song.
Michael, you never told me
you knew Johnny Fontane.
- Sure. You wanna meet him?
- Huh? Oh, well, sure.
My father helped him
with his career.
- For my Connie.
- He did? How?
I have but one
- Let's listen to the song.
- No.
Heart
This heart I bring you
I have but one heart
To share with you
I have but one dream
That I can cling to
You are the one dream
I'll pray comes true
Please, Michael. T ell me.
My darling, until I saw you
When Johnny
was first starting out...
he was signed to this
personal service contract...
with a big bandleader.
And as his career
got better and better...
he wanted to get out of it.
Now, Johnny is
my father's godson...
and my father went
to see this bandleader...
and he offered him
$10,000 to let Johnny go.
But the bandleader said no.
So the next day
my father went to see him...
only this time
with Luca Brasi.
And within an hour,
he signed a release...
for a certified check of $1,000.
How'd he do that?
My father made him an offer
he couldn't refuse.
What was that?
Luca Brasi
held a gun to his head...
and my father assured him
that either his brains...
or his signature
would be on the contract.
That's a true story.
That's my family, Kay.
It's not me.
Beautiful!
My godson comes all the way
from California.
Give him a glass of wine.
I'll take care of it.
I want you to find Santino.
Tell him to come to the office.
How are you, Fredo?
My brother Fredo.
This is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How ya doin'?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah.
This is your friend, huh?
I don't know what to do.
My voice is weak.
It's weak.
Anyway, if I had this part
in the picture...
it puts me right back
up on top again.
But this...
this man out there,
he won't give it to me.
- The head of the studio.
- What's his name?
Woltz.
He won't give it to me...
and he says
there's no chance, no chance.
Sonny?
Sonny, you in there?
- What?
- The old man wants to see you.
Yeah, one minute.
A month ago, he bought
the movie rights to this book.
A best-seller.
And the main character
is a guy just like me.
Why, I wouldn't even
have to act.
Just be myself.
Oh, Godfather,
I don't know what to do.
You can act like a man!
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out?
A Hollywood finocchio
that cries like a woman?
"What can I do?"
What is that nonsense?
Ridiculous!
- You spend time with your family?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because the man who doesn't
spend time with his family...
can never be a real man.
Come here.
You look terrible.
I want you to eat.
I want you to rest well,
and a month from now...
this Hollywood big shot's
gonna give you what you want.
Too late.
They start shooting in a week.
I'm gonna make him an offer
he can't refuse.
Now just go outside,
enjoy yourself...
and forget about
all this nonsense.
Listen. I want you
to leave it all to me.
All right.
What time does my daughter
leave with the bridegroom?
In a few minutes,
right after they cut the cake.
Now, your new son-in-law,
we give him something important.
Never.
Give him a living...
but never discuss
the family business with him.
What else?
Virgil Sollozzo called.
We have to give him a day
sometime next week.
We'll discuss him when you
come back from California.
When am I going to California?
I want you to go tonight.
I want you to talk
to this movie big shot...
and settle this business
for Johnny.
If there's nothing else, I'd like
to go to my daughter's wedding.
Carlo, we're gonna take
the picture.
Wait a minute.
No, Michael, not me.
Just a little closer.
Okay, that's it.
Just like that now. Hold it.
Isn't that nice?
All right, start talking.
I was sent by a friend
of Johnny Fontane.
This friend is my client and would
give his undying friendship...
to Mr. Woltz if Mr. Woltz
would grant us a small favor.
Woltz is listening.
Give Johnny the part in that new
war film you're starting next week.
And what favor
would your friend...
grant Mr. Woltz?
You're gonna have
some union problems.
My client
could make them disappear.
Also, one of your top stars
has just moved...
from marijuana to heroin.
- Are you trying to muscle me?
- Absolutely not.
Listen to me,
you smooth-talking son of a bitch!
Let me lay it on the line for you
and your boss, whoever he is!
Johnny Fontane
will never get that movie.
I don't care
how many dago, guinea, wop...
greaseball goombahs
come outta the woodwork.
I'm German-Irish.
Well, let me tell you something,
my kraut mick friend.
I'll make so much trouble for you,
you won't know what hit you.
I'm a lawyer.
I have not threatened-
I know almost every big lawyer
in New York. Who are you?
I have a special practice.
I handle one client.
Now, you have my number.
I'll wait for your call.
By the way, I admire
your pictures very much.
Check him out.
- This is really beautiful.
- Look at this.
Used to decorate
the palace of a king.
Oh, yeah. Very nice.
Why didn't you say
you worked for Corleone, Tom?
I thought you were just
some cheap, two-bit hustler...
Johnny was running in,
trying to bluff me.
I don't like to use his name
unless it's really necessary.
- How's your drink, Tom?
- Fine.
Come with me. I want to show you
something really beautiful.
You do appreciate beauty,
don't you, Tom?
There you are.
$600,000 on four hooves.
I'll bet Russian czars...
never paid that kind of dough
for a single horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not gonna race him, though.
I'm gonna put him out to stud.
Beautiful.
- Thanks, Tony.
- You're welcome.
- Come on.
- Let's get something to eat.
Mr. Corleone
is Johnny's godfather.
To the Italian people,
that's a very religious...
sacred, close relationship.
I respect that.
Just tell him he should ask me
anything else.
This is one favor
I can't give him.
He never asks a second favor
when he's been refused the first.
- Understood?
- You don't understand.
Johnny Fontane
never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him.
It'll make him a big star.
I'm gonna run him
out of the business.
Let me tell you why.
Johnny Fontane ruined
one of Woltz International's...
most valuable proteges.
For five years,
we had her under training.
Singing lessons,
acting lessons, dancing lessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands
of dollars on her.
I was gonna make her
a big star.
And let me be
even more frank.
Just to show you that I'm not
a hard-hearted man...
that it's not all
dollars and cents.
She was beautiful.
She was young, she was innocent!
She was the greatest piece of ass
I've ever had...
and I've had 'em
all over the world!
And then Johnny Fontane
comes along...
with his olive oil voice
and guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me look ridiculous...
and a man in my position
can't afford...
to be made
to look ridiculous!
Now you get the hell outta here!
And if that goombah
tries any rough stuff...
you tell him
I ain't no bandleader.
Yeah. I heard that story.
Thank you for the dinner
and a very pleasant evening.
If your car could take me
to the airport...
Mr. Corleone is a man who insists
on hearing bad news immediately.
- You're not too tired, Tom?
- No, I slept on the plane.
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
Now...
Sollozzo is known as
"The Turk. "
He's supposed to be
very good with a knife...
but only
in matters of business...
with some sort
of reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey
where they grow the poppy...
and in Sicily he has the plants
to process them into heroin.
Now, he needs cash and he needs
protection from the police...
for which he gives
a piece of the action.
I couldn't find out how much.
The Tattaglia family
is behind him here in New York.
Now, they have to be
in it for something.
Santino Corleone.
What about his prison record?
Two terms,
one in Italy, one here.
He's known as
a top narcotics man.
Santino, what do you think?
There's a lot of money
in that white powder.
Tom?
I say, yes, there's more
money potential in narcotics...
than anything else
we're looking at.
If we don't get into it,
somebody else will.
Maybe one of the five families,
maybe all of them.
With the money they earn...
they can buy more police
and political power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have the unions,
we have the gambling...
and they're the best things
to have, but narcotics...
is a thing of the future.
If we don't get
a piece of that action...
we risk everything we have.
Not now, but ten years from now.
So? What's your answer
gonna be, Pop?
I need a man
who has powerful friends.
I need a million dollars in cash.
I need, Don Corleone,
those politicians...
that you carry in your pocket
like so many nickels and dimes.
What is the interest
for my family?
Thirty percent.
In the first year, your end
should be 3, 4 million dollars.
And then it would go up.
And what is the interest
for the Tattaglia family?
My compliments.
I'll take care of the Tattaglias
outta my share.
So, I receive 30%
for finance...
political influence
and legal protection.
- That's what you're telling me.
- That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider
a million dollars in cash...
just "finance"-
I said that I would see you
because...
I heard that you were
a serious man...
to be treated with respect.
But I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true, I have
a lot of friends in politics.
But they wouldn't be friendly
very long...
if they knew my business was drugs
instead of gambling...
which they regard
as a harmless vice.
- But drugs is a dirty business.
- No, Don Corleone-
It doesn't make
any difference to me...
what a man does for a living,
you understand...
but your business is...
a little dangerous.
If you’re worried about security
for your million...
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
You're tellin' me the Tattaglias
guarantee our investment-
Wait a minute.
I have a sentimental weakness
for my children...
and I spoil them,
as you can see.
They talk when they should listen.
But anyway...
Signor Sollozzo,
my "no" is final...
and I wish to congratulate you
on your new business.
I know you'll do very well,
and good luck to you...
especially since your interests
don't conflict with mine.
Thank you.
Come here.
What's the matter with you?
I think your brain
is going soft...
from all that comedy you're
playing with that young girl.
Never tell anybody outside the
family what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom, what-
What is this nonsense?
It's from Johnny.
He's starring in that new film.
Well, take it away.
Take it over there.
And...
tell Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a little worried
about this Sollozzo fellow.
I want you to find out what
he's got under his fingernails.
Go to the Tattaglias...
and make them think...
that you're not too happy
with our family...
and find out what you can.
And I got something
for your mother and for Sonny...
and a tie for Freddy...
and Tom Hagen
got the Reynolds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- Me?
Oh, just you.
Tell Paulie to get the car.
We're going.
Okay, Pa.
I'll have to get it myself.
Paulie called in sick this morning.
Paulie's a good kid.
I don't mind gettin' the car.
Luca, I am Bruno Tattaglia.
I know.
Scotch? Prewar.
You know who I am?