- Merry Christmas.
- Yeah.
I'm glad I run into you.
I wanna talk to you.
I haven't got time.
Oh, make time, consigliere.
Get in the car.
What are you worried about?
If I wanted to kill you,
you'd be dead already.
Get in.
- I'm gonna buy some fruit.
- Okay, Pa.
Hi. Merry Christmas.
I want some fruit over there.
Gimme three of them.
No, that one.
Fredo!
Papa.
Papa!
Would you like me better
if I were a nun...
like in the story, you know?
Then would you like me better
if I were Ingrid Bergman?
Now that's a thought.
No, I would not like you better
if you were Ingrid Bergman.
- Mike-
- What's the matter?
They don't say
if he's dead or alive.
- Sonny, Michael.
- Michael, where you been?
Is he all right?
We don't know yet.
There's all kinds of stories.
He was hit bad, Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
Where you been?
I was worried.
Didn't Tom tell you?
I called.
No. Look, come home, kid.
You should be with Mama, you hear?
All right.
Oh, my God.
Go. Who is it?
Open up. It's Clemenza.
What?
There's more news
about your old man.
The word is out on the street
he's already dead.
Shut your mouth.
What's the matter with you?
Jesus Christ!
Take it easy.
- Where was Paulie?
- Paulie was out sick.
- He's been sick all winter.
- How many times he been sick?
Only maybe three, four times.
I asked Freddy if he wants
a different bodyguard.
- He said no.
- Pick him up now.
I don't care how sick he is.
If he's breathin', I want you to
bring him to my father's house now.
- You want me to send people here?
- No, just you and him. Go ahead.
All right.
I'm havin' a couple of our people
come to the house.
- Hello?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
In about three hours, he'll be
released with our proposition.
Listen to everything he has
to say before you do anything.
What's done is done.
And don't lose that famous temper
of yours, huh, Sonny?
No, I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in
the muscle end of the family...
so I don't want you
to be scared.
I want you
to help the Corleones...
and I want you to help me.
We got him outside his office...
about an hour after
we picked you up.
Drink it.
So now it's up to you to make
the peace between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot
for my deal, wasn't he?
And you knew it was
the right thing to do.
Sonny will come after you
with everything he's got.
That'll be
his first reaction, sure.
That's why you gotta
talk some sense into him.
The Tattaglia family is behind me
with all their people.
The other New York families
will go along with anything...
that will prevent
a full-scale war.
Let's face it,
in all due respect...
the Don, rest in peace,
was slippin'.
Ten years ago,
could I have gotten to him?
Well, now he's dead.
He's dead,
and nothing can bring him back.
So you gotta talk to Sonny.
You gotta talk
to the caporegimes-
that Tessio,
that fat Clemenza.
It's good business, Tom.
I'll try.
But even Sonny won't be able
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah. Well-
Let me worry about Luca.
You just talk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
I'll do my best.
Good.
Now, you can go.
I don't like violence, Tom.
I'm a businessman.
Blood is a big expense.
He's still alive.
They hit him with five shots,
and he's still alive!
Well, that's bad luck for me...
and bad luck for you
if you don't make that deal.
Your mother's over
in the hospital with your father.
Looks like he's gonna
pull through, thank God.
- That's a lot of bad blood.
- What do you think?
It's too far.
I think it's too personal.
- The Don will consider this over.
- You gonna kill all those guys?
- Stay out of it, Mickey.
- Sollozzo's the key.
You get rid of him,
everything falls into line.
What about Luca? Sollozzo
didn't seem worried about Luca.
I don't know. If Luca sold out,
we're in a lot of trouble.
Has anyone been able
to get in touch with Luca?
We've been tryin' all night.
He might be shacked up.
Mick, try him again.
Luca never sleeps over
with a broad.
He always goes home
when he's through.
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
What do we do
if the old man dies, God forbid?
If we lose the old man...
we lose our political contacts
and half our strength.
The other New York families might
wind up supporting Sollozzo...
just to avoid
a long destructive war.
This is almost 1946.
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
you'll make the deal, Sonny.
That's easy for you to say.
He's not your father.
I was as much a son to him
as you or Mike.
What is it?
Hey, Paulie, I thought
I told you to stay put.
The guy at the gates,
they say they got a package.
Yeah?
Tessio, go see what it is.
- You want me to hang around?
- Yeah, hang around.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Yeah? There's some food
in the icebox. You hungry?
- No, it's all right. Thanks.
- How 'bout a little brandy?
- That's good to sweat it out.
- Sure.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
I want you to take care
of that son of a bitch right away.
Paulie sold out the old man.
I don't wanna see him again.
Make that first thing on your list.
Understood.
Hey, Mickey, tomorrow
you get a couple of guys.
Go to Luca's apartment.
Wait for him to show up.
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directly.
Yeah.
Listen, hang around the house
on the phone. It'll be a big help.
Try Luca again. Go ahead.
- What the hell is this?
- It's a Sicilian message.
It means Luca Brasi
sleeps with the fishes.
- I'm goin' now.
- What time you gonna be home?
I don't know. Probably late.
- Don't forget the cannoli.
- Yeah, yeah.
Rocco, sit on the other side.
You block the rearview mirror.
Sonny's runnin' wild.
He's thinkin' of goin'
to the mattresses already.
We gotta find a spot
over on the West Side.
We'll try
309 West 43rd Street.
You know any good spots
on the West Side?
- Yeah, I'll think about it.
- Think while you're drivin'.
I wanna hit New York
sometime this month.
And watch out for the kids
when you're backin' out.
Paulie, I want you to go
down 39th Street. Colosanto's.
Pick up 18 mattresses for the guys
to sleep. Bring me the bill.
- Yeah, all right.
- Make sure they're clean.
Those guys are gonna be stuck up
in there for a long time.
They're clean. They told me
they exterminate them.
"Exterminate"?
That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate. Get this guy.
See how we don't exterminate you.
- Youse funny, or what?
- Hey, Paulie?
- Yeah, Rocco, what'd you do?
- No, me. It wasn't me.
- It's gotta be him.
- Pull over.
I gotta take a leak.
Leave the gun.
Take the cannoli.
- Yeah?
- You're wanted on the telephone.
- Who is it?
- It's some girl.
Hello, Kay?
How's your father?
He's good.
He's gonna make it.
I love you.
I love you!
- Michael?
- Yeah, I know.
Tell me you love me.
- I can't talk.
- Can’t you say it?
Yeah, I'll see you tonight.
Why don't you tell
that nice girl you love her?
I love you
with all o' my heart!
If I don't see you again a-soon,
I'm-a gonna die!
Come over here, kid.
Learn somethin'.
You might have to cook
for 20 guys someday.
You see? You start out
with a little bit of oil.
Then you fry some garlic.
Then you throw in some tomatoes,
some tomato paste.
You fry it.
You make sure it doesn't stick.
When you got it to a boil, shove in
all your sausage and meatballs.
And a little bit of wine.
And a little bit of sugar.
- And that's my trick.
- Why don't you cut the crap?
I got more important things
for you to do.
- How's Paulie?
- Won't see him no more.
- Where you going?
- To the city.
Send some bodyguards with him.
- I'm just going to see Pop.
- Send somebody with him.
He'll be all right.
Sollozzo knows he's a civilian.
- All right. Be careful, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
I have to go.
Can I go with you?
No, Kay. There's gonna be
detectives there.
People from the press.
I'll ride in a cab.
I don't want you
to get involved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire...
and I'll call you
at your parents' house.
When will I see you again,
Michael?
I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed
to be here now.
I'm Michael Corleone.
This is my father.
There's nobody here.
What happened to the guards?
Your father just had
too many visitors.
They interfered
with hospital service.
The police made them leave
about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 4-5-6-2-0,
please.
Nurse, wait a minute.
Stay here.
Sonny, Michael.
I'm at the hospital.
Listen. I got here late.
There's nobody here.
Nobody. No Tessio's men,
no detectives, nobody.
- Pop is all alone.
- Don't panic. We'll send somebody.
I won't panic.
I'm sorry, but you will
have to leave.
You and I are gonna move my father
to another room.
Can you disconnect those tubes
so we can move the bed out?
- That's out of the question.
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here
to kill him.
You understand?
Now, help me, please.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo- the baker.
- You remember me?
- Enzo?
- Yes, Enzo.
- You better get out of here, Enzo.
There's gonna be trouble.
If there is trouble,
I stay here to help you-
For your father.
All right, listen.
Wait for me outside,
in front of the hospital.
All right? I'll be out
in a minute. Go ahead.
Just lie here, Pop.
I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these.
Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket
like you have a gun.
You'll be all right.
You'll be okay.
You did good.
Here he is.
All right, hold still.
I thought I got
all you guinea hoods locked up.
What are you doing here?
What happened to the men who
were guarding my father, Captain?
Why, you little punk.
What the hell are you doing,
telling me my business?
I pulled them guys off
of here.
You get out of here
and stay away from this hospital.
I'm not moving until you put
some guards around my father's room.
Phil, take him in.
The kid's clean, Captain.
He's a war hero.
- He's never been busted-
- Goddamn it, I said take him in.
What's the Turk paying you
to set up my father, Captain?
Take ahold of him.
Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the attorney
for the Corleone family.
These men are private detectives
hired to protect Vito Corleone.
They're licensed to carry
firearms.
If you interfere, you'll have to
appear before a judge...
in the morning
and show cause.
All right, let him go.
Come on.
What's with all the new faces?
Gonna need 'em now.
After the hospital thing,
Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno Tattaglia
at 4:00 this morning.
Jesus Christ.
Looks like a fortress
around here.
A hundred button men on the street,
24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair
on his ass, he's dead. Believe me.
Hey, Michael, come here.
Let me look at you.
You look beautiful.
Just beautiful.
You're gorgeous.
Hey, listen to this.
The Turk, he wants to talk.
Imagine the nerve
on this son of a bitch.
Craps out last night,
he wants a meeting today.
- What'd he say?
- What did he say?
He wants us to send Michael
to hear the proposition.
And the promise is that the deal
is so good that we can't refuse.
What about Bruno Tattaglia?
That's part of the deal.
Bruno cancels out what they did
to my father.
Sonny, we ought to hear
what they have to say.
No more.
Not this time, Consigliere.
No more meetings, no discussions,
no more Sollozzo tricks.
You give them one message-
I want Sollozzo.
If not, it's all-out war.
We go to the mattresses.
Some of the other families
won't sit still for a war.
- Then they hand me Sollozzo.
- Your father wouldn't like this.
- This is business, not personal.
- They shot my father.
Even shooting your father
was business, not personal, Sonny.
Well, then business
will have to suffer.
And do me a favor, Tom-
No more advice on how
to patch things up.
Just help me win, please.
All right?
I found out about this McCluskey
who broke Mike's jaw.
What about him?
He's definitely on Sollozzo's
payroll, and for big money.
McCluskey has agreed
to be the Turk's bodyguard.
What you have to understand,
Sonny...
is that while Sollozzo's
being guarded like this...
he is invulnerable.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York police captain. Never.
It would be disastrous. All the
five families would come after you.
The Corleone family
would be outcast.
Even the old man's political
protection would run for cover.
So do me a favor.
Take this into consideration.
All right, we'll wait.
We can't wait.
Can't wait.
I don't care what Sollozzo says
about a deal.
He's gonna kill Pop.
That's it.
That's the key for him.
Got to get Sollozzo.
Mike is right.
Let me ask you something first.
What about this McCluskey?
What do we do
with this cop?
They want to have a meeting
with me, right?
It will be me...
McCluskey and Sollozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be held.
We insist it's a public place-
a bar, a restaurant.
Someplace where there's people,
so I feel safe.
They're gonna search me
when I first meet them, right?
So I can't have a weapon
on me then.
But if Clemenza can figure a way...
to have a weapon
planted there for me...
then I'll kill them both.
What are you gonna do?
Nice college boy, huh?
Didn't want to get mixed up
in the family business.
Now you want to gun down
a police captain?
Why? 'Cause he slapped you
in the face a little bit?
Do you think this is the army,
where you shoot them a mile away?
You gotta get up close,
like this and-
You blow their brains all over your
nice Ivy League suit. Come here.
You're taking this
very personal.
Tom, this is business, and this man
is taking it very, very personal.
Where does it say
you can't kill a cop?
- Come on, Mikey.
- Tom, wait a minute.
I'm talking about a cop
that's mixed up in drugs.
I'm talking about a dishonest cop,
a crooked cop...
who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming to him.
That's a terrific story.
We have newspaper people
on the payroll, don't we, Tom?
They might like
a story like that.
They might.
They just might.
It's not personal, Sonny.
It's strictly business.
It's as cold as they come.
Impossible to trace, so you don't
worry about prints, Mike.
I put a special tape
on the trigger and the butt.
Here. Try it.
What's the matter,
the trigger too tight?
- My ears.
- I left it noisy.
That way it scares pain-in-the-ass
innocent bystanders away.
All right, you shot them both.
Now what do you do?
Sit down, finish my dinner.
Come on, kid.
Don't fool around.
Just let your hand drop to your side
and let the gun slip out.
Everybody will still think
you got it.
They're gonna be staring
at your face, Mike...
so walk out of the place real fast,
but you don't run.
Don't look nobody directly in the
eye, but don't look away, either.
They're gonna be scared stiff
of you, believe me...
so don't worry about nothing.
You know, you're gonna turn out
all right.
You take a long vacation,
nobody knows where...
and we're gonna catch
the hell.
How bad do you think
it's gonna be?
Pretty goddamn bad.
Probably all the other families
will line up against us.
That's all right. These things
gotta happen every five years or so.
Ten years.
Helps to get rid of the bad blood.
Been ten years since
the last one.
You gotta stop them
at the beginning...
like they should have
stopped Hitler at Munich.
They should have never let him
get away with that.
They was just asking
for big trouble.
You know, Mike,
we was all proud of you...
being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing.
Not a hint.
Absolutely nothing.
Even Sollozzo's people don't know
where the meeting will be held.
How much time do we have?
Gonna pick you up in front
of Jack Dempsey's joint...
in an hour and a half-
exactly an hour and a half.
We could put a tail on them,
see how it turns out.
Sollozzo'll lose our ass
going around the block.
What about the negotiator?
He's over at my place playing
pinochle with a couple of my men.
He's happy.
They're letting him win.
It's too much of a risk for Mike.
Maybe we ought to call it off.
The negotiator keeps playing cards
until Mike's back safe and sound.
Why doesn't he blast who's ever
in the goddamn car?
Too dangerous.
They'll be looking for that.
Sollozzo might not
even be in the car, Sonny.
I got it.
Yeah.
- Louis Restaurant in the Bronx.
- Is it reliable?
That's my man
in McCluskey's precinct.
A police captain's got to be
on call 24 hours a day.
He signed out at that number
between 8:00 and 10:00.
Anybody know this joint?
Yeah, sure. I do.
It's perfect for us.
A small family place,
good food.
Everyone minds his business.
It's perfect.
Pete, they got
an old-fashioned toilet-
You know, the box
and the chain thing.
We might be able
to tape the gun behind it.
All right.
Mike, you go to the restaurant.
You eat, you talk for a while,
you relax.
You make them relax.
Then you get up
and go take a leak.
No, better still,
you ask for permission to go.
And when you come back,
you come out blasting.
And don't take any chances.
Two shots in the head apiece.
Now, listen.
I want somebody good-
and I mean very good-
to plant that gun.
I don't want him coming out
with just his dick in his hands.
The gun will be there.
All right, listen. You drive him
and you pick him up after the job.
Come on. Let's move.
Thank you, Tom.
Did he tell you
to drop the gun right away?
Yeah, a million times.
Don't forget-
two shots apiece in the head...
as soon as you
come out the door.
Let's go.
How long do you think it'll be
before I can come back?
At least a year, Mike.
Listen, I'll square with Mom you
not seeing her before you leave...
and I'll get a message
to that girlfriend...
when I think the time is right.
Take care.
- See you, Mike.
- Okay, Tom.
I'm glad you came, Mike.
I hope we can
straighten everything out.
This is terrible. It's not the way
I wanted things to go at all.
It should have
never happened.
I want to straighten
everything out tonight.
I don't want my father
bothered anymore.
He won't be, Mike.
I swear on my children he won't be.
But you got to keep an open mind
when we talk.
I hope you're not a hothead
like your brother Sonny.
You can't talk business
with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry about
the other night, Mike.
I gotta frisk you,
so turn around, huh?
On your knees,
facing me.
I guess I'm getting
too old for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's clean.
We're going to Jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work, Lou.
How's the Italian food
in this restaurant?
Good.
Try the veal.
- It's the best in the city.
- I'll have it.
I'm gonna speak Italian
to Mike.
Go ahead.
What I want-
what's most important to me-
is that I have a guarantee:
no more attempts
on my father's life.
What guarantees could I give you?
I am the hunted one.
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me, kid.
I'm not that clever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is that all right?
You gotta go, you gotta go.
I frisked him.
He's clean.
Don't take too long.
I've frisked a thousand
young punks.